Hey English learners, welcome to this A1
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing great. Today, we're going
to talk about beginner English listening
practice content for beginners, people
who are at a beginner level in their
English learning. If you're not a
beginner, if you're a little bit of a
higher level, then still watch this
video because it will still be useful
for you. And at the end, I'm going to
ask you something if you're at a higher
level. So, watch until the end. So,
first of all, what is a beginner? Who is
a beginner when it comes to
English learning and listening
comprehension? Well, a beginner in
general is someone who is new to
something. Someone who is not very
experienced.
However, it doesn't always mean that
you're starting from zero.
That is an absolute beginner.
Many beginners are not absolute
beginners, and they already know uh and
have skills in some different areas.
And so, for listening practice, uh a
beginner might already understand
a lot of words, a lot of phrases, but
maybe they don't have a lot of
experience listening, and they can't
understand English when it's spoken
quickly. So,
who is this video for? When I say this
is for beginners, who am I talking
about? Well,
uh
if you
can't understand fast English,
and you need
to listen to content that's slower and
clearer,
then this is
uh the type of content that you will
want to listen to.
Um and if you're trying to increase your
vocabulary,
these types of videos will be very
helpful for you.
This video will have words
that a beginner might not understand. Uh
you might not know some of the words
that I'm saying,
and this is okay.
All right? Because we need to learn to
use resources that will help us
understand content that is a little
challenging for us. So, for example, you
need to learn how to look up words and
translate them, define them. These are
tools that help us as language learners.
So, you shouldn't just say, "Well, I
don't know these words, so I can't watch
this video." No. You need to learn how
to
copy and paste
new words, or write
these new words into a translator like
WordReference or Google Translate and
learn how to
use these tools to help you understand
the content that you're listening to.
So, the subtitles also
make a big difference because you can
see the words that I'm saying and that
should help you when you're looking up
words and trying to understand what I'm
saying. You can pause
the video, right, to see the new word
and then look it up and then maybe
rewind, go back and then listen again.
It's important to be active when you're
practicing your listening. Don't just
watch something and say, "Nah, I don't
know that word. I don't know that word.
I don't know that word."
and not do anything. You should be
active. Look up the new words. Try to
understand the meaning of what the
person is saying. So,
me for example, I'm learning Greek
and I do not have a high level of Greek.
But, I'm trying to get to a higher
level.
So,
what I do is
I use content that challenges me.
Content that is higher than my
current level, my current knowledge of
Greek. So,
I have to look up words all the time. I
have to pause, rewind, look up words,
rewind, pause, press play.
I do this for hours
every week. And
I don't use content that I can
understand 100%.
That's not what I'm interested in.
I use content that has words that I
don't know,
that is challenging for me,
so that I can reach the next level.
This is why my A1 videos
contain more vocabulary than
other beginner content that you'll find
uh online, okay? Uh the reason why I do
this is because my philosophy is that
you need to actively challenge yourself
to learn new words, expand your
vocabulary,
learn new concepts, so that you can
reach a higher level.
If you only listen to content that
contains words that you know,
that's not really helping you improve
your vocabulary, increase your
knowledge. You need to challenge
yourself and learn to be active and look
up new words.
I don't have a high level in Greek, but
I'm using native content, interviews
between two people
that uh where the people are speaking
fast and it takes me a long time to
finish the video
uh because I pause, look up words,
rewind, look up words, pause,
all of that,
but
I can actually
use that content and understand most of
it when I'm active and looking up words,
and it's helping me
reach a higher level.
That's what you should try to do
if you are at the A1 level, if you're a
beginner.
You should actively try to increase your
level
of listening, right? So,
I like making content that is natural,
like this video. It's natural, but it's
slow, and I uh don't use as much uh
vocabulary
variations and
big words. I use some, but not as much.
I limit myself, and I speak very slowly,
but this is natural.
This does not feel like content from a
school textbook that you use in your
English class, right? Um I want you to
get used to listening to a person
who is speaking naturally, like me,
slow, but natural, right? Um and some
people uh don't like that I do this.
They criticize,
meaning they talk negatively about my
style, uh what I just said, that I make
A1 videos that are hard, but
come on, if you want to get better
at something, you need to challenge
yourself. In my opinion, if you're at an
A1 level, you shouldn't be using A1
content
that is super easy for you. How does
that help you reach the next level? It
doesn't. If you're at an A1 level, you
should try your hardest to get to the
next level.
So, in order to do that, you have to try
to expand your vocabulary
and listen to things that are harder
than the normal A1 content, and that
have more words, more new things. That's
how we improve. That's what I'm doing as
a language learner. That's what I did
for French. That's what I'm doing for
Greek. That is how you can improve your
listening.
Be active. Use resources like
translators.
And
you should use this type of challenging
content. So, yes,
these videos that I title A1 are harder
than the typical A1 video, but there's a
reason for that, because you don't want
to stay at A1, right? You want to go up
and reach the next level. That's why I
make content like this that is a little
more challenging than other A1 content.
So, what if this video, this content is
easy for you? Well,
you need to use harder content. Okay?
There's no question about it. If this is
easy for you, then you need to use more
difficult content. And I make content
for [clears throat] everyone, for all
levels on this channel.
You can look at the playlists and see my
A2 videos, in which I speak a little bit
faster. And then my B1 videos, which are
just me speaking at normal speed. Okay?
I also have advanced podcast episodes,
right? I always leave the link down
below if you want to sign up for those.
So,
content for more advanced learners as
well.
But, I also
had the idea, I don't know if I'm going
to do this, but I wanted to mention it
to see what you think. I might start
doing some live videos,
in which I speak at normal speed, and I
can interact a little with my audience.
You can write comments, ask questions,
and I can interact a little bit,
and answer some questions,
and it will be native level. I'll be
speaking at normal speed. It will be
very natural.
There won't be subtitles.
But,
I'm still easier to understand than
other
native speakers. I'm sure you would
agree. So,
I think it would still be more
um
or it'll be easier than other native
level content. And I already make native
level content, like I just mentioned. My
B1 content, my advanced episodes.
Uh but
I'm kind of interested in trying lives.
So, we'll see. Um
if you're interested in that, if you
have a higher level and you want that
content, uh tell me in the comments,
because I'm interested to see if people
actually want me to do that or not. I
don't know if I will do it, but I wanted
to ask to see if people are interested
in that. So,
tell me what you think.
I hope that you enjoyed this video and
that you understand this philosophy
of using challenging content, being
active, looking up words to help you
reach the next level. If you want my
advanced podcast episodes, that link is
down below, so click on that. Thank you
all for listening and I'll talk to you
in the next video.